Bangura drive, Old School, Freetown, Rep. of SIERRA LEONE

🛘 (+232) 74-714-198 | 💌 abdulrahmanj40@gmail.com | 🖸 abdulj40 | 🛅 ajalloh-10 | Nationality: Sierra Leonean

"If the preferable is not available, let the available be preferable"

Summary

A Data Scientist in Sierra Leone with 2+ years experience specializing in Data Analysis and Visualization, Web Development, and Business Intelligence. Super curious who loves to work with data and helping businesses and organizations make better and more informed decisions. Interested in continuous learning and development, and spreading knowledge.

Work Experience __

Directorate of Science, Technology, and Innovation

Freetown, Sierra Leone

Nov. 2020 - Present

JUNIOR DATA SCIENTIST CONSULTANT

- · Analyze data to improve its understanding and impacts on policies and programs
- · Build dashboards that analyzes real-time or near real-time data and trends that impact decision making
- · Standardize, transform, and analyze data that sits on the Education Data Hub A hub that tracks annual exams performance, and key school
- · Analyze and report on geospatial data for the integrated Geographic Information System (iGIS) portal
- Develop and maintain algorithms and data pipeline scripts that streamlines the process of cleaning and transforming data
- Visualize and report data findings creatively in a variety of formats.
- Develop data requirements, data dictionaries, and data models for different projects.
- Use predictive analytics to provide time-series analysis and predictions on identified indicators or outcomes.
- · Design and build models to predict pregnant women susceptible to maternal mortality in Pregnancy and Services Tracker (PreSTrack) Project.

Directorate of Science, Technology, and Innovation

Freetown, Sierra Leone

DATA SCIENCE INTERN

Mar 2020 - Oct 2020

- · Develop and maintain data cleaning and processing pipeline for the integrated Geographic Information System (iGIS) portal
- Clean and analyze the Annual School Census and Exams data for the Education Data Hub
- Perform data studies and data discovery around new data sources or new uses for existing data sources.

Freelancing Freetown, Sierra Leone

WEB DEVELOPER & DATA ANALYST

Mar. 2017 - Present

- Develop bespoke web applications for individuals, businesses and organizations.
- Develop internal dashboards for organizations to measure key performance indicators and streamline better and faster decision making.
- · Coach and train college colleagues, employees of different institutions on introductory courses to web development and data analysis with excel and python.

Education

Njala University, Freetown Campus

Freetown, Sierra Leone

Oct. 2016 - Jun. 2020

B.S. (Hons) in Business Information Technology · Graduated with First Class Honours.

WorldQuant University

APPLIED DATA SCIENCE MODULE

Louisiana, United States

Jan. 2020 - Jun. 2020

- Scientific Computing and Python for Data Science
- · Machine Learning and Statistical Analysis

International Business Machines (IBM) and Coursera

New York, United States

IBM DATA SCIENCE - PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE

Nov. 2020 - Dec. 2021

• Capstone Project: SpaceX Falcon 9 Landing Outcome Prediction

Skills & Abilities

DATA SCIENCE

Language, Python programming language

Libraries, Pandas, numpy, matplotlib, seaborn, folium, plotly, scitkit-learn

Environment, Jupyter notebook, Google collab, Apache zeppelin, ArcGIS Online Desktop, Anaconda, Excel

Visualization, Elastic Kibana, Superset, Google Looker, Google Studio, Metabase, Tableau, PowerBI

Desktop, ArcGIS Online

WEB DEVELOPMENT

Languages, Python, Javascript, HTML

Databases, Postgresql, MySQL, SQL Server, SQLite, IBM DB2

Frontend, Bootstrap, Materializecss, ReactJs, CSS

Libraries and Frameworks, Django, Django restframework(API Development)

Version Control:, Git, GitHub

AWARDS AND HONORS

2020 Award, Arctic Code Vault Contributor

By GitHub

Extracurricular Activity _____

SLICDEV INC.

CO-FOUNDER AND CEO

· Slicdev focuses on providing cutting edge software and data solutions for people, businesses, and organizations.

Reading latest articles and books

BLOGS, ARTICLES AND BOOKS ON TECHNOLOGY, BUSINESS, SOCIAL ENTERPRISE, CREATIVITY, INNOVATION, AND MINDSET

Sports

AVID FOOTBALL FAN, WATCHING FOOTBALL MATCHES

Referees

Mr. ISSA B. FOFANA +232-78-914650

SENIOR LECTURER & COMPUTER SCIENTIST, NJALA UNIVERSITY

Dr. YAKAMA MANTY JONES +232-79-121480

DIRECTOR OF RESEARCH & DELIVERY, MINISTRY OF FINANCE, GOVERNMENT OF SIERRA LEONE